# MUHAMMAD AHSAN

+1(647) 836-3077  $\diamond$  Toronto, ON

ahsant2709@gmail.com \leftrightarrow linkedin.com/in/muhammad-ahsan \leftrightarrow

#### **SUMMARY**

A skilled programmer with a 3-year diploma (6 semester) in computer programming and analysis, seeking full-time web / software developer roles. Experienced in generating and unit testing web applications using Angular, React, .Net, Node.js, linux, Bootstrap and Oop languages.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Diploma in Computer Prgamming and Analysis, Seneca College

2020 - 2022

Honors List summer 2021 4.0 GPA.

#### **SKILLS**

Technical Skills
Tools
Soft Skills

JavaScript, Typescript, C, C++, C#, .NET, Java, Angular, React, HTML, CSS, Python Azure, Aws, Cloud, Eclipse, Visual studio, SQL, APIs, GitHub, MicroServices, Agile, Oracle Customer Service, English, Attention to detail, Problem-Solving, Research, collaborative

## **EXPERIENCE**

Sales Associate
Hudson's Bay Company

April 2022 - Current

Toronto, ON

- Achieved 30% growth for Neo credit card applicants using customer service skills.
- Process customer purchase requests, using knowledge of customer fit, product knowledge, attention to detail, and POS, gaining 5 of 5 stars business customer experience rating.

Lab Assistance Seneca College Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

Toronto, ON

- Reduced 15% search times for SQL database searches using relational data.
- Led better user experience in assignment submission which led to 20% decreased of incomplete lab submissions.
- Developed example projects that helped students understand assignments end goal.

### **PROJECTS**

Bronx-Burgers (React NodeJs) Generated burger ordering app, using knowledge of user authentication, cart management, payment processing with react, MongoDB, HTML, NodeJS, and collaboration with client, delivering 100% performance efficiency with modular development! (Try it here) (Github)

Music Biz (ASP.NET) Created a role based .net music app separated into Front-End & Back-End - Full stack to hold your favourite artists data (Artist details, tracks and albums) categorized by genre which is linked using MySQL relational database overall following service-oriented architecture. (Try it here)(GitHub)

**Prime Calendar (Angular NodeJs) - collaborate Project** Lead a team of developers in generating and designing a user-friendly online studying aid application using a calender rest Api, Angular, Typescript, relational data structures (Mongo db), Node js, which boosts productivity by over 30%. (Try it here) (Github)

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Actively participate in coding competitions on discord servers like the Competitive Programming community with more than 20,000 current members
- Participation in 2022 beginner Hackathon college competition